HARRISON MILLER

San Francisco, CA • 9546323386 • hmaxmiller@gmail.com

hmaxmiller.com



Yale '17. 3+ year React/ES6 front-end developer. Technical Consultant @ Celena. Strongly interested in UI Engineering & Product roles.

Summary

Fast learner specializing in front-end development, technical consulting, research methods, and Agile/SCRUM methodologies. 3+ years of experience in JavaScript, React/React Native, HTML & CSS, and C, with desire to learn new languages and tools enthusiastically as needed. Demonstrated ability in acquiring business knowledge and using data-driven approaches to product development. Successfully led consulting team of Yale engineers and designers to build software applications for small and medium-sized businesses.

Hungry to take on the challenge of a lifetime. Authorized to work in the U.S. for any employer.

Technical Skills

- JavaScript/ES6/ES7
- React/React Native
- Bootstrap
- C

- Front-End Development
- Technical Consulting
- Research Methods
- Agile/SCRUM

- Microsoft Office
- Sketch
- Waffle.io
- Trello

Experience

2016 - 2017

Technical Consultant & React Native Mobile Developer

Celena

Led technical assessments and software development for Celena consultancy client projects (https://www.celena.co/#team). Specialty in full-stack JavaScript applications using React, React Native, and Node.

- Facilitated a data-driven approach toprioritize and implement front-end features in the product development cycle for client MVPs.
- Spearhead the implementation of software applications based on functional, design, and technical specifications.
- Supervise and manage performance of team of designers, engineers, and contractors focused on optimizing service to client base.

2014 - 2016

Developer & UX Researcher

Various Early Stage Companies

Received \$10000 in fellowships to build out MVPs for early stage student ventures, including Venture (collegiate activities-based social networking app), Membra (public speaking anxiety solution), and Celestrix (VR archery training simulator)

- Execute MVP development based on user feedback and market analysis, often with completion in under 4 months.
- Executed on full product design cycle by defining product requirements, creating user flow

- diagrams, and producing high-fidelity prototypes.
- Collaborated with an engineering team by leading biweekly development sprints as well as conducting full QA assessments of each release.
- Defined and monitored product usage KPIs to inform subsequent product iterations.

2014 - 2015 Front-End Engineer

Yale University

- Designed, built, and optimized author website for Stephen S. Roach, former Chief Economist & Chairman of Morgan Stanley Asia, to promote new book (Unbalanced: The Codependency of America and China).
- Increased site traffic and conversion KPI's for book purchases with targeted SEO strategies
- Implemented and maintained search functionality based on timsort & Rabin-Karp string matching for database of 100+ op-ed articles.

2012 - 2014 Earlier Experience

Associate Brand Manager

iXperience

 Advised branding campaigns on product positioning, sample size, and demographic targets. Worked with CEO and COO to manage and prioritize growth initiatives for coding bootcamp, selling out the programunder 5 months.

Organic Chemistry Researcher

Miller Lab at Yale University

• Invented and tested a new chiral phosphoric acid catalyst that improved conversion rate of reactions by roughly 34%.

Education

2012 - 2017 Bachelor of Arts

Yale University

Joint Psychology & Computer Science program in Psychology department focusing on *Human-Computer Interaction*. Read thesis here: https://www.hmaxmiller.com/HumorEvaluationsHCI.pdf

Community Involvement

- National Society of Black Engineers
 Elected Member, Yale University Chapter
- Yale Entrepreneurial Institute Venture Creation Program, \$2500 Fellowship
- YHack Hackathon Event Organizer (1500+ hackers)
- Research Fellowships \$5000 Miller Lab Fellowship, \$1000 Richter Fellowship, \$1000 Babcock Fellowship

Activities

- Yale University Archery Team Founder & Captain: fundraised over \$7500, hired nationally certified coach, recruited fellow officers, and regulated budget operations for equipment and competition expenses.
- Yspaniola Volunteered to build education infrastructure for communities in Batey Libertad, Dominican Republic.